Alexandra G. TREMBLAY-McGAW

PERSONAL INFORMATION

WEBSITE: https://atrembla.github.io/index.html

EMAIL: atrembla@stanford.edu

CURRENT POSITION

MAY 2021-CURRENT Lead Clinical Research Coordinator (CRC-2), STANFORD UNIVERSITY, Palo Alto, CA

Biobehavioral Pediatric Pain Lab - Laura Simons, Ph.D

Oversee all lab activities and projects; collect and analyze fMRI data; coordinate simultaneous studies and supervise data collection and participant recruitment; train, oversee, schedule, and mentor multiple CRC-A's and undergraduate research assistants. Work with graduate students,

post-docs, and faculty across institutions and universities.

EDUCATION

SEP 2014-MAY 2018 Bachelor of Arts in Psychology, Skidmore College, Saratoga Springs, NY

magna cum laude and honors within the major

Thesis: "The Integration of Memories in the Human Brain"

Advisor: Dr. Daniel Peterson GPA: 3.9 Detailed List of Courses

SEP 2014-MAY 2018 Bachelor of Arts in Economics, Skidmore College, Saratoga Springs, NY

magna cum laude and honors within the major

Thesis: "An Examination of Homelessness and Mental Illness"

Advisor: Dr. Sandra Goff GPA: 3.8 | Detailed List of Courses

JAN 2017-MAY 2017 Semester Abroad, Universidad Autónoma de Madrid, Madrid, Spain

Skidmore Tufts: in Spain Gpa: 3.7 Detailed List of Courses

AUG 2003-MAY 2012 Student and Dancer, San Francisco Ballet School, San Francisco, CA

full scholarship pre-professional dancer with various solos

CLINICAL EXPERIENCE

APR 2022-CURRENT Clinical Interviewer, JOURNEY IN PAIN CARE STUDY, Stanford, CA

Biobehavioral Pediatric Pain Lab - Laura Simons, Ph.D

Interviewed parents and pediatric patients with chronic pain about their pain care journey in

semi-structured clinical interviews.

Jan 2017-May 2017 Volunteer, Asociación Española Contra Cáncer, Madrid, Spain

Hospital Infanta Sofía - Patricia Pradera, Ph.D

Visited cancer patients; took notes about their demeanor and reported to head psychologist regarding the patients' emotional state and well-being. Provided information to patients and families regarding hospital and government services and aid. All communication

conducted in Spanish.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

MAY 2021-CURRENT

Lead Clinical Research Coordinator (CRC-2), STANFORD UNIVERSITY, Palo Alto, CA Biobehavioral Pediatric Pain Lab - Laura Simons, Ph.D

Project: Signature for Pain Recovery in Teens - SPRINT

DESCRIPTION: SPRINT is a multisite, international effort to uncover a biological signature predicting pain recovery and persistence in teens with musculoskeletal pain. In collaboration with the University of Toronto, Hospital for Sick Children (SickKids), and Cincinnati Children's Hospital, we are using a novel machine learning technique to generate and test a elastic net model, opening doors for new screening and treatment approaches. SPRINT participation consists of a blood draw, an hour-long MRI, sensory testing, and parent and child questionnaires in person, and biweekly surveys for three months at home. **CONTRIBUTION:** As the Lead Coordinator of the SPRINT study, I manage and oversee study recruitment, data collection, database management, and multiple team meetings. I work to standardize procedures, coordinate blood transfers, and facilitate all data analysis by collating the data, merging, and cleaning it. I assist with the writing and submission of progress reports to the NIH. Additionally, I am leading an independent project on representation in the recruitment of this study.

Project: Learning and Memory in Pediatric Chronic Pain

DESCRIPTION: Given the influential role of learning and memory on pain outcomes in youth with chronic pain, the goal of the current study is to examine the process of aversive learning in adolescents with pain in comparison to healthy individuals. This study utilizes brain imaging (fMRI), psychophysical (skin conductance), and saliva cortisol measures to assess functional circuit and physiological changes associated with altered learning and memory patterns.

CONTRIBUTION: I have managed data analysis for this study and contributed to multiple manuscripts and posters that are products of this study, including an independent project examining threat learning in the cerebellum in youth with chronic pain and pain-free peers.

Project: Pain Rehabilitation Virtual Reality - PRVR

DESCRIPTION: In collaboration with Stanford Children's Health, Agile Physical Therapy, and California Rehabilitation & Sports Therapy, this randomized controlled trial will examine a novel approach to pain management through the use of virtual reality (VR) technologies. We expect to address factors relevant to chronic pain, including increasing range of motion, reducing pain-related fear of movement, and improving the mind-body connection. VR tools for pain have shown promise in numerous research studies and our mission is to continue to improve care for children and adolescents with chronic pain. **CONTRIBUTION:** For this clinical trial I assisted with study start-up and initializing regulatory and IRB contracts and protocols. I helped develop the protocol and best uses for VR in Physical Therapy. I trained and oriented study staff and physical therapists. Additionally, I helped write the published protocol paper.

Project: Journey in Pain Care

DESCRIPTION: Journey in Pain Care aims to conduct formative research to identify opportunities for better care among youth with chronic pain and their families. Our goal is to characterize-with in-depth interviews and longitudinal quantitative data-the experiences of youth living with chronic MSK pain and their parents who are seeking and completing multidisciplinary pain care. The purpose is to highlight gaps in care, communication, and understanding that should be further studied.

CONTRIBUTION: I trained to become a clinical interviewer on the study, assisted with regulatory affairs, participated in bi-weekly group supervision to further develop and build upon clinical and research skills.

Jun 2018-Aug 2021

Lab Manager, The University of Oregon, Eugene, OR The Kuhl Lab - Brice Kuhl, Ph.D

Project: *DIPPER*

DESCRIPTION: DIPPER aims to examine to what extent representations of imagined events resemble representations of retrieved events. We used fMRI pattern similarity analyses to compare neural representations of retrieved and imagined events. In the course of one study visit, participants were scanned while watching videos, remembering previously viewed videos, and imagining novel events conceptually related to the content of watched and remembered videos.

CONTRIBUTION: I participated in the development of this research idea, the planning of the study design, and I collected all of the imagining data. The manuscript is in preparation.

Project: PEMS EEG

DESCRIPTION: In PEMS EEG, we tested whether encoding and retrieval biases can be decoded from patterns of neural activity and whether decoded evidence of memory biases predicts how new events will be remembered. During an EEG session, participants were first familiarized with a series of common objects. Afterwards, subjects completed a continuous recognition task that included 'old' and 'new' objects. The order of stimulus presentation was controlled such that half of the new objects were preceded by an old object and half were preceded by a new object. Following continuous recognition, participants completed a post-test that required discriminating objects from the continuous recognition task vs. perceptually similar lures.

CONTRIBUTION: I collected the PEMS EEG data and worked to check the data quality and analyze the data. I submitted an abstract and presented a poster of our results.

Project: ColorSep

DESCRIPTION: In ColorSep, we tested whether similarity between events triggers adaptive biases in how those events are remembered. We generated pairs of competing objects that were identical except in color and varied the degree of color similarity for the competing objects. Across a series of several experiments, subjects repeatedly studied and were tested on associations between each of these objects and corresponding faces.

CONTRIBUTION: For ColorSep, I collected all of the data, implemented study design changes, worked to trouble shoot MatLab errors, and assisted with figure generation for the final manuscript.

SEP 2016-MAY 2018

Research Assistant & Lab Manager, SKIDMORE COLLEGE, Saratoga Springs, NY Memory and Learning Sciences Lab - Daniel Peterson, Ph.D

Project: Physiological Stress and Face Recognition

DESCRIPTION: In two experiments, participants encoded faces either under physiological stress (via a cold pressor task) or under control conditions. Participants were later given a recognition memory test for the faces and provided confidence judgments in their old/new decisions.

CONTRIBUTION: While working in the lab, I managed data collection, oversaw the training of research assistants, and discussed study design and implementation.

Project: Memory Integration

DESCRIPTION: In the Memory Integration experiment, we implemented a repeated measures design to assess the impact of seeing a positive version of a negative event. Sixty-three participants participated in a for-credit or paid experiment advertised as a study on "emotional processing" that consisted of viewing a series of negative, positive, or neutral images of scenes while having their skin conductance measured. **CONTRIBUTION:** This was my senior year honors thesis that I conceptualized, designed, implemented, analyzed, presented, and wrote up.

MANUSCRIPTS

- **Tremblay-McGaw, A.G.**, Biggs, E.E., Timmers, I., Moulton, E., & Simons, L.E., (in preparation). *The role of the cerebellum in threat learning in youth with chronic pain.*
- **Tremblay-McGaw, A.G.**, Biggs, E.E., Goya Arce, A., & Simons, L.E., (in preparation). *Representation in chronic pain experimental research.*
- Timmers, I., Bruckert, L., Biggs, E.E., **Tremblay-McGaw, A.G.**, Borsook, D., Zhang, H., & Simons, L.E. (in press). A comprehensive interrogation of neurite microstructure in youth with chronic pain: multi-shell diffusion weighted imaging.
- Simons, L.E., Hess, C.W., Choate, E.S., Van Orden, A.R., **Tremblay-McGaw**, **A.G.**, Menendez, M., Boothroyd, D.B., Griffin, A., Parvathinathan, G., Griffin, A., Caruso, T.J., Stinson, J., Weisman, A., Liu, T., Christensen, R., & Koeppen, K., (in press). *Virtual Reality Augmented Physiotherapy for Chronic Pain in Youth: Protocol for a randomized controlled trial enhanced with single case experimental design*. Journal of Medical Internet Research.
- Chanales, A.J.H., Tremblay-McGaw, A.G., Drascher, M.L., & Kuhl, B.A. (2020). *Adaptive repulsion of long-term memory representations is triggered by event similarity.* Psychological Science. 32 (5), 705-720.

POSTERS

- **Tremblay-McGaw, A.G.**, Harrison, L.E., & Simons, L. (in preparation). *Sleep and Individual Dif- ferences in Youth with Chronic Pain.* Poster session TBD, presenting at the Social and Affective Neuroscience Society Annual Meeting.
- **Tremblay-McGaw, A.G.**, Biggs, E.E., Goya Arce, A., Sokol, O., Wiseman, A.M., & Simons, L.E., (2022, September). *Representation of chronic pain populations in experimental research*. Poster PWD310, presented at the IASP World Congress on Pain, Toronto, Canada.
- **Tremblay-McGaw, A.G.**, Biggs, E.E., Timmers, I., Moulton, E., & Simons, L.E., (2022, September). *The role of the cerebellum in threat learning in youth with chronic pain.* Poster PFR155, presented at the IASP World Congress on Pain, Toronto, Canada.
- Madgavkar, D. Hess, C.W., Van Orden, A.R., Wiseman, A.M., **Tremblay-McGaw, A.G.**, Choate, E.S., & Simons, L.E., (2022, August). *Journey in Pain Care (JiPC): A qualitative protocol for examining the lived experiences of children and families navigating chronic pain treatment.* Poster session A, presented at the Stanford Bio-X Interdisciplinary Annual Symposium, Palo Alto, California.
- **Tremblay-McGaw, A.G.**, Biggs, E.E., Simons, L.E., & Timmers, I. (2022, May). Alterations in white matter microstructure for youths with chronic pain relate to pain catastrophizing: an evaluation of diffusion MRI data using multi-compartment modelling. Poster session VIII, presented at the Association for Psychological Science Annual Convention, Chicago, IL.
- Choate, E., Hess, C., Van Orden, A., **Tremblay-McGaw**, **A.G.**, Griffin, A., Feinstein, A., Caruso, T., & Simons, L. (2022, April). *Virtual reality in physical therapy: A randomized clinical trial*. Poster session III, presented at the Society for Pediatric Psychology, Pheonix, AZ.

- Molitor, R.J., Tremblay-McGaw, A.G., DuBrow, S., & Kuhl, B.A. (2020, March). *Distributed representations of remembered vs. imagined events*. Poster session A, presented at the Cognitive Neuroscience Society, Boston, MA.
- Drascher, M.L., **Tremblay-McGaw**, **A.G.**, & Kuhl, B.A. (2019, October). *Repulsion and sharpening along diagnostic feature dimensions support resolution of memory interference*. Poster session 169, presented at the Annual Society for Neuroscience, Chicago, IL.
- **Tremblay-McGaw, A.G.**, Kuhl, B.A., & Long, N.M. (2019, March). *Decoding biases between memory encoding and retrieval induced by recent experience*. Poster session A, presented at the Annual Cognitive Neuroscience Society, San Francisco, CA.
- **Tremblay-McGaw**, **A.G.**, Wissman, K.T., & Peterson, D.J. (2018, November). *The integration of memories in the human brain*. Poster session IV, presented at the Annual Psychonomic Society, New Orleans, LA.

INVITED SEMINARS

Hoffman, H., Van Orden, A.R., Hess C.W., Tremblay-McGaw, A.G., & Simons, L.E. (2022, September). *The Powers and Application of Virtual Reality: A Special Hands-On Workshop*. Presented at the Pediatric Sedation and Pediatric Dental Sedation Symposium: Boston Children's Hospital Harvard Medical School Teaching Hospital "Outside of the Operating Room" Conference, San Francisco, CA.

Honors and Awards

Nov 2018	Travel to Present Award Skidmore College (USD \$700)
Jan 2018	Mary Shafer Dennis Endowed Scholarship Skidmore College (USD \$5,440)
SEP 2017	Foley Psychology Department Research Fund Skidmore College (USD \$300)
MAR 2017	See Beyond Award Skidmore College (USD \$4,000)
2015-2018	Dean's List Honors Skidmore College
2014-2018	Tuition Exchange Scholarship Skidmore College (USD \$134,500)
2014-2018	Skidmore College Grant Skidmore College (USD \$43,702)
2010-2014	Scholarship to attend Drew High School (USD \$128,000)
2003-2012	Full scholarship to attend the San Francisco Ballet School (USD \$100,000)

TRAINING

June 2021-Current	Bloodborne Pathogens Certification, Stanford School of Medicine
June 2021-Current	HIPPA for Researchers and Protecting Patient Privacy Certification,
	Stanford School of Medicine
June 2021-Current	MRI Safety Certification, Stanford University
June 2021-Current	CITI Basic Training Course for Biomedical Research & GCP Training,
	Stanford University
MAY 2021	Bystander Intervention to Stop Anti-Asian/American Harassment
	and Xenophobia Training, Hollaback
OCT 2019	NSF GRFP Workshop, University of Oregon
AUG 2019	Philips Neuro HD EEG Workshop, University of Oregon
MAY 2017-2021	CITI Basic Training Course for Biomedical Research, University of Oregon
MAY 2017-2021	MRI Safety Certification, University of Oregon

COMPUTER SKILLS

Basic Knowledge: MATLAB, SPSS, LTEX, LIVECODE, PYTHON, R, JASP

Intermediate Knowledge: Adobe, Excel, Word, PowerPoint

Toolboxes: CONN, SUIT, JASP, MARSBAR

MEMBERSHIPS

MAY 2022-CURRENT International Association for the Study of Pain

NOV 2021-CURRENT Society of Pediatric Psychology
MAR 2020-CURRENT Association for Psychological Science
NOV 2018-NOV 2020 Cognitive Neuroscience Society

JUL 2018-JUL 2020 Society for Neuroscience JUL 2018-JUL 2019 Psychonomic Society

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH: Fluent SPANISH: Fluent

REFERENCES

Laura Simons, PhD

Professor, Stanford University School of Medicine

PHONE: 650.736.0838

EMAIL: lesimons@stanford.edu

Lauren Harrison, PhD

Instructor, Stanford University School of Medicine

PHONE: 281.777.4120

EMAIL: agoyaarc@stanford.edu

Ana Goya Arce, PhD

Instructor, Stanford University School of Medicine

PHONE: 510.806.3409

EMAIL: leharr@stanford.edu

Emma Biggs, PhD

Post Doctoral Fellow, Stanford University

PHONE: 669.249.1814

EMAIL: eebiggs@stanford.edu

Courtney Hess, PhD

Post Doctoral Fellow, Stanford University

PHONE: 650.497.6896

EMAIL: cwhess@stanford.edu

Brice Kuhl, PhD

Professor, University of Oregon

PHONE: 541.346.4983

EMAIL: bkuhl@uoregon.edu

Daniel Peterson, PhD

Associate Professor, Skidmore College

PHONE: 919.622.4326

EMAIL: dpeters2@skidmore.edu

Nicole Long, PhD

Assistant Professor, University of Virginia

PHONE: 434.982.4799

EMAIL: niclong@virginia.edu

Kathryn Wissman, PhD

Assistant Professor, North Dakota State University

PHONE: 614.738.5793

EMAIL: kathryn.wissman@ndsu.edu

Sandra Goff, PhD

Assistant Professor, Skidmore College

PHONE: 518.580.5095

EMAIL: sgoff@skidmore.edu

Bachelor of Arts in Psychology, Skidmore College

Courses

Introduction to Psychological Science
Research Methods in Psychology I
Abnormal Psychology
Colloquium in Psychological Science
Social Psychology
Research Methods in Memory
Clinical Psychopharmacology
Psychology of Race
Senior Research Project I
Senior Research Project II

Bachelor of Arts in Economics, Skidmore College

Courses

Introduction to Macroeconomics
Introduction to Microeconomics
Calculus I
Macroeconomic Theory
Statistical Methods
Advanced Macroeconomic Theory and Policy
Evolutionary Economics
Income Distribution
Pre-Thesis
Environmental and Resource Economics
Senior Seminar

Exchange Program, Universidad Autónoma de Madrid

Courses

Clinical Psychology